<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Buffer Data Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Buffer Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites     Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile      https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile      https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README     This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
 https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud     Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) [1] ‘0.2.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdoown&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;)  Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection  My layout is: single-series   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buffer&#39;s Free Users</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-06-20-buffer-s-free-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-06-20-buffer-s-free-users/</guid>
      <description>There are four main goals for this data analysis:
 Better understand Buffer&amp;rsquo;s active free user base Identify opportunities for converting free users to paid Map our free user onboarding actions Define cohorts within our free user base to inform user qualification  There are a lot of sections below, so settle in with a cup of tea and enjoy. Thank you in advance for reading this and taking the time to learn about Buffer&amp;rsquo;s free users!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographic Market Insights</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-05-10-geographic-market-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-05-10-geographic-market-insights/</guid>
      <description>Hello. The purpose of this analysis is to gain a better understanding of Buffer’s customer penetration in various countries and regions around the world. We would like to learn what markets we are doing well in and which have room for improvement.
This analysis should help guide budget allocation decisions related to paid marketing by country and capture insights to guide our &amp;ldquo;market prioritization&amp;rdquo; framework for market development/expansion and penetration efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the New User Experience in Buffer</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-04-06-understanding-the-new-user-experience-in-buffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-04-06-understanding-the-new-user-experience-in-buffer/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis we&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to gain a better understanding of how new users interact with Buffer, identify behavior patterns that are indicative of success and share a few recommendations for how to improve the experience.
Over the course of this analysis we&amp;rsquo;ll look at paid conversion rates, activation rates, the relationships between feature usage and conversion rates, session duration, upgrade paths, the distribution of the time it takes to convert, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Channels Connected at Point of Conversion</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-02-14-channels-connected-at-point-of-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-02-14-channels-connected-at-point-of-conversion/</guid>
      <description>The data team recently received several questions that we&amp;rsquo;ll try to answer in this analysis:
  What is the average number of channels connected at the point of conversion vs. 3 months of subscription? How does it differ for people that signed up with and without a trial?
  What effect does an additional channel have on revenue? For example, if the current average is 1.2 channels and we increased that to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution of Conversion Time</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-02-02-distribution-of-conversion-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-02-02-distribution-of-conversion-time/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis we&amp;rsquo;ll analyze the distribution of the amount of time it takes new Buffer users to subscribe to a paid plan.
This data is censored in nature &amp;ndash; there are people that will convert to paid plans that have yet to do so &amp;ndash; however, for the purpose of this analysis, we&amp;rsquo;ll look only at paying customers that have had at least six months to convert.
Data Collection     The dataset we&amp;rsquo;ll use in this analysis contains around 259 thousand users that subscribed to a paid plan at some point before August 2021 (six months ago).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Subscription Rates</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-01-24-analysis-of-subscription-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-01-24-analysis-of-subscription-rates/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis we’ll analyze the rate at which new signups subscribe to paying plans on Buffer. We will also examine how long it takes for new users to subscribe.
28-Day Subscription Rate First we’ll look at subscription rates. For each weekly cohort of new users, we’ll calculate the proportion that paid for a subscription within 28 days of signing up.
# load data customers &amp;lt;- readRDS(&amp;quot;subscription_rates.rds&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% mutate(converted = subs &amp;gt;= 1) The plot below shows the proportion of weekly new users that susbcribed to a paid plan within 28 days of signing up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of NPS Survey Responses</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-01-19-analysis-of-nps-survey-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-01-19-analysis-of-nps-survey-responses/</guid>
      <description>In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll analyze 7166 NPS survey responses gathered from Pendo. We&amp;rsquo;ll find the most frequently occurring words for Promoters, Passives, and Detractors, and calculate which of them are most unique to each segment. We&amp;rsquo;ll also visualize networks of terms that commonly occur together.
Tidy Text Data Format     In order to analyze the text efficiently, we&amp;rsquo;ll want to make use of some &amp;ldquo;tidy&amp;rdquo; data principles. To consider this data set tidy we need to have one token (or one observation in most other analyses) per row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Subscription Churn in New Buffer</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-01-19-analysis-of-subscription-churn-in-new-buffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-01-19-analysis-of-subscription-churn-in-new-buffer/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis we will analyze the subscription churn rates of New Buffer subscriptions. We&amp;rsquo;ll use a well known technique called survival analysis that&amp;rsquo;s useful when dealing with censored data.
Censoring occurs when we have some information about the time it takes for the key event to occur, but we do not know the survival time exactly. In our case, it occurs when subscriptions have not yet canceled &amp;ndash; we know that the time to churn is at least X days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A campfire</title>
      <link>/talk/campfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/campfire/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to give this talk! Stay tuned for video and slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>/talk/second-seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/second-seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>/talk/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tachyons for Style</title>
      <link>/project/giraffes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/giraffes/</guid>
      <description>Tachyons is a design system that allows you to design gorgeous interfaces in the browser with little effort.      Because Speed     Building this static site generator theme was the first time I used an Atomic (or Functional) CSS system like Tachyons. It&amp;rsquo;s a design system that provides very small (which means fast) CSS modules that you can use in your HTML. So, rather than writing every line of CSS, you apply the style you need as you write your HTML with easy to understand shorthand class names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palmer Penguins</title>
      <link>/project/penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/penguins/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.”     — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
 Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bakeoff</title>
      <link>/project/bakeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bakeoff/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website.      Functional Form     This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
   Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
   Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
   Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
