<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Le Blog on Buffer Data Blog</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Le Blog on Buffer Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Buffer&#39;s Free Users</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-06-20-buffer-s-free-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-06-20-buffer-s-free-users/</guid>
      <description>There are four main goals for this data analysis:
 Better understand Buffer&amp;rsquo;s active free user base Identify opportunities for converting free users to paid Map our free user onboarding actions Define cohorts within our free user base to inform user qualification  There are a lot of sections below, so settle in with a cup of tea and enjoy. Thank you in advance for reading this and taking the time to learn about Buffer&amp;rsquo;s free users!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geographic Market Insights</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-05-10-geographic-market-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-05-10-geographic-market-insights/</guid>
      <description>Hello. The purpose of this analysis is to gain a better understanding of Buffer’s customer penetration in various countries and regions around the world. We would like to learn what markets we are doing well in and which have room for improvement.
This analysis should help guide budget allocation decisions related to paid marketing by country and capture insights to guide our &amp;ldquo;market prioritization&amp;rdquo; framework for market development/expansion and penetration efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the New User Experience in Buffer</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-04-06-understanding-the-new-user-experience-in-buffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-04-06-understanding-the-new-user-experience-in-buffer/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis we&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to gain a better understanding of how new users interact with Buffer, identify behavior patterns that are indicative of success and share a few recommendations for how to improve the experience.
Over the course of this analysis we&amp;rsquo;ll look at paid conversion rates, activation rates, the relationships between feature usage and conversion rates, session duration, upgrade paths, the distribution of the time it takes to convert, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Channels Connected at Point of Conversion</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-02-14-channels-connected-at-point-of-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-02-14-channels-connected-at-point-of-conversion/</guid>
      <description>The data team recently received several questions that we&amp;rsquo;ll try to answer in this analysis:
  What is the average number of channels connected at the point of conversion vs. 3 months of subscription? How does it differ for people that signed up with and without a trial?
  What effect does an additional channel have on revenue? For example, if the current average is 1.2 channels and we increased that to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution of Conversion Time</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-02-02-distribution-of-conversion-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-02-02-distribution-of-conversion-time/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis we&amp;rsquo;ll analyze the distribution of the amount of time it takes new Buffer users to subscribe to a paid plan.
This data is censored in nature &amp;ndash; there are people that will convert to paid plans that have yet to do so &amp;ndash; however, for the purpose of this analysis, we&amp;rsquo;ll look only at paying customers that have had at least six months to convert.
Data Collection     The dataset we&amp;rsquo;ll use in this analysis contains around 259 thousand users that subscribed to a paid plan at some point before August 2021 (six months ago).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Subscription Rates</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-01-24-analysis-of-subscription-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-01-24-analysis-of-subscription-rates/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis we’ll analyze the rate at which new signups subscribe to paying plans on Buffer. We will also examine how long it takes for new users to subscribe.
28-Day Subscription Rate First we’ll look at subscription rates. For each weekly cohort of new users, we’ll calculate the proportion that paid for a subscription within 28 days of signing up.
# load data customers &amp;lt;- readRDS(&amp;quot;subscription_rates.rds&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% mutate(converted = subs &amp;gt;= 1) The plot below shows the proportion of weekly new users that susbcribed to a paid plan within 28 days of signing up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of NPS Survey Responses</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-01-19-analysis-of-nps-survey-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-01-19-analysis-of-nps-survey-responses/</guid>
      <description>In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll analyze 7166 NPS survey responses gathered from Pendo. We&amp;rsquo;ll find the most frequently occurring words for Promoters, Passives, and Detractors, and calculate which of them are most unique to each segment. We&amp;rsquo;ll also visualize networks of terms that commonly occur together.
Tidy Text Data Format     In order to analyze the text efficiently, we&amp;rsquo;ll want to make use of some &amp;ldquo;tidy&amp;rdquo; data principles. To consider this data set tidy we need to have one token (or one observation in most other analyses) per row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Subscription Churn in New Buffer</title>
      <link>/blog/2022-01-19-analysis-of-subscription-churn-in-new-buffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022-01-19-analysis-of-subscription-churn-in-new-buffer/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis we will analyze the subscription churn rates of New Buffer subscriptions. We&amp;rsquo;ll use a well known technique called survival analysis that&amp;rsquo;s useful when dealing with censored data.
Censoring occurs when we have some information about the time it takes for the key event to occur, but we do not know the survival time exactly. In our case, it occurs when subscriptions have not yet canceled &amp;ndash; we know that the time to churn is at least X days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
